# ADEBAYO ADEOLA

Halifax, NS | B3S 1J8 | 782-414-0745 | bayocana@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/adebayo-adeola

## **PROFILE**

Data Analyst with more than 3 years experience in Power BI, Python, SQL, sales, banking operations, business intelligence and software development. A dedicated professional with training in Business Intelligence and Analytics with strong analytical and problem-solving abilities. I also possess diverse technical skills necessary to collaborate with various departments and explaining complex concepts to non-technical stakeholders.

#### **SKILLS**

- **Business Analysis:** Business requirements gathering, elicitation & documentation, use cases and documenting business processes
- Business Intelligence: Power BI, Power Query, DAX, Python, Tableau, MS Excel
- Database Development: PLSQL/T-SQL: functions, stored procedures, MS SQL Server, Mongo DB, SSIS, SSRS
- Cloud Computing: Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services
- Agile/SCRUM: Git, GitHub, Jira, Jenkins
- **Application Development:** debugging and testing experience, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, React Native, Electron, Expo
- Operating Systems: Linux, Mac, Bash scripting, DOS
- **Data Mining and Statistical Analysis:** Data Warehouse, ETL, Regression, Clustering, Classification, Logistic Regression, Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn
- **CRM:** Salesforce Admin

**Soft Skills:** Excellent written and verbal communication skills. Strong interpersonal relationship skills. A continuous and willing learner as shown in my academic trainings and certifications.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Data Analytst, Teaching Assistant Skills for Hire, Digital Nova Scotia

06/2023 - Date

- Training on Python for Data Analysis to alter CSV files or Excel spreadsheets, ransposing and pivoting data
- Teaching hands-on Data Visualization and Data Reporting with PowerBI reporting and Tableau
- Teaching Data Modeling: Implementing database models with DAX (Data Analysis Expressions)
- Tutoring Machine Learning; Natural Language Processing with Python
- Tutoring cloud technologies and services Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Relational Database Management training and Data Quality Management with MS SQL Server.

### **Data Analyst (Volunteer)**

## Data for Good Maritimes, Halifax, Nova Scotia

05/2023 - Date

- Understanding business data and maintaining the integrity and quality of the data
- Data Analysis, Data Profiling and Interpretation: Analyze raw data, manipulate data sets, and interpret results to provide insightful, data-driven business solutions.
- Using SQL queries, Power Query, DAX and PowerBI to ascertain data quality, perform data migration and integration
- Business documentations and readme files for data manipulation and visualization
- Using Slack as a collaborative tool to share files and communicate
- Designing, Developing and Maintaining BI Solutions: Developing data analytics platforms; dashboards, reports, and metrics using Microsoft Power BI.
- Data Integration: Connect multiple data sources, integrating them into a unified, understandable dataset. Implement row-level security on data and have an understanding of application security layer models in Power BI.

## **Peer Assisted Learning Support**

02/2022 - 04/2023

Nova Scotia Community College, IT Campus, Halifax, Nova Scotia.

- Taught JavaScript, Python, Business Intellience & Analytics and Structured Query Language
- Taught designing, Developing and Maintaining BI Solutions: Developing data analytics platforms; dashboards, reports, and metrics using Microsoft Power BI and Microsoft SSRS.
- Taught Data Integration: Connect multiple data sources including time series and other datasets; CSV and other text files, spreadsheets and various data files, integrating them into a unified, understandable dataset. Implement row-level security on data and have an understanding of application security layer models in Power BI.
- Teaching data warehouse concepts; ETL processes with integration tools; SSIS and MS SQL Server.

## **Summer Scholarship Awardee**

### Research Nova Scotia

04/2023 - 06/2023

- Created a Mobile App PracticeHealthNS
- Used Google Firestore and Google Authentication back-end
- Used React-Native framework and libraries to design front-end

## **Collaborator, Exchanges and Returns**

08/2022 - Date

IKEA, Halifax, Nova Scotia.

- Customer service that is committed, responsive, articulate, reliable and responsive
- · Actively listen to customers and discover their needs, process transactions in accordance with IKEA's policies
- Collaborates with team members through Sharepoint and teams to meet service goals

# Relationship Manager

01/2018 - 08/2021

Zenith Bank PLC, a global Financial Institution with head-office in Nigeria.

www.zenithbank.com

*Business Strategy:* Achieved 75 % of sales target by developing and integrating targeted online and offline lead generation programs

Business Development: Mobilized deposits and sold various bank's products and services

Leadership: Co-ordinated and managed a team of 6 Relationship Managers

Relationship Management: Identified, established and developed relationship with individuals and companies Business Intelligence and Analytics: Used Power Query (MS Excel) to visualize branch's clients performance against previous months, quarters and years, generated SQL Scripts (Stored Procedures) to retrieve trends in customers' transactions profiles

Financial Advisory: provided financial advisory services to customers with integrity and innovation

## **EDUCATION**

Post Graduate Certificate (Honors), Full Stack Application Development. 05/2023

NSCC, Nova Scotia

Post Graduate Certificate (Honors), Business Intelligence and Analytics. 06/2022

NSCC, Nova Scotia.

EduNova Study and Stay (Participant) 07/2023

Training, mentorship and networking to understand the diverse culture of the workplace and business

ISANS - Immigration Services Association of Nova Scotia (Client) 05/2023

*Understanding workplace culture, diversity, equity and inclusion. Career workshops* 

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Fundamentals of Agilile Project Management 03/2023

Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals 07/2022

Power Platform Fundamentals 07/2022

AI Fundamentals 08/2022

Microsoft Office User Specialist (MOUS, Microsoft Excel) 12/2018.

Project Management Professional (PMP) 07/2017